<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automation on API Mocking and Testing | Microcks.io</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/</link><description>Recent content in Automation on API Mocking and Testing | Microcks.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Connecting to Microcks API</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/api/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/api/</guid><description>Overview This guide shows you how to authenticate to and how to use the Microcks API for better automation of tasks. As all the features available in Microcks can be used directly through its REST API, you can extend it we way you want and use it in a pure headless mode.
This guide takes place in 3 steps:
1️⃣ We will check your security configuration and see if authentication is required (it depends on how you deployed Microcks),</description></item><item><title>Using Microcks CLI</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/cli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/cli/</guid><description>Overview This guide illustrates usage of microcks-cli, a command-line tool for interacting with Microcks APIs. It allows to launch tests or import API artifacts with minimal dependencies. It is managed and released independently of the core Microcks server components within its own GitHub repository. The CLI connects to API and uses Service Account and so it&amp;rsquo;s definitely worth the read 😉
The CLI also supports authenticated and non-authenticated mode when Microcks is deployed without Keycloak.</description></item><item><title>Using in GitHub Actions</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/github-actions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/github-actions/</guid><description>Overview This guide shows you how to integrate Microcks into your Github Actions workflows. Microcks provides 2 GitHub Actions for interacting with a Microcks instance from your workflows:
The Microcks Import GitHub Action allows you to import Artifacts in a Microcks instance. If import succeeds is pursuing, if not it fails,
The Microcks Test GitHub Action allows you to launch a Microcks test on a deployed API endpoint. If test succeeds (ie.</description></item><item><title>Using in Jenkins Pipeline</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/jenkins/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/jenkins/</guid><description>Overview This guide illustrates how you can integrate the Microcks Jenkins plugin keep Microcks in-sync withe your API specifications and integrate tests stages within your Jenkins CI/CD pipelines. This plugin allows your Jenkins builds and jobs to import API Artifacts into a Microcks instance and to launch new Tests. It uses Service Account and so it&amp;rsquo;s definitely worth the read 😉
The Microcks Jenkins plugin has its own GitHub repository and its own lifecycle.</description></item><item><title>Using in GitLab CI</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/gitlab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/gitlab/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Using in Tekton Pipeline</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/tekton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/automation/tekton/</guid><description>Overview This guide shows you how to integrate Microcks into your Tekton Pipelines. Microcks provides 2 Tekton Tasks for interacting with a Microcks instance. They allow you to:
Import Artifacts in a Microcks instance. If import succeeds is pursuing, if not it fails, Launch a test on a deployed API endpoint. If test succeeds (ie. API endpoint is conformant with API contract in Microcks) the workflow is pursuing, if not it fails.</description></item></channel></rss>