<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Microcks.io</title>
    <link>https://microcks.io/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Microcks.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://microcks.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.2.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.2.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.2.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to announce the 1.2.0 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. With this new release, we are pursuing further our vision of a unique tool and consistent approach for speeding up the delivery and governing the lifecycle of ALL kinds of APIs - whether synchronous or asynchronous.
In this release, we put a lot of effort (and love ❤️) into listening and implementing feedback and ideas from our community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Dispatching and Constraints for mocks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/advanced-dispatching-constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/advanced-dispatching-constraints/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to explain the advanced dispatching and constraint features available when mocking a REST API using Microcks. As I recently went again through the documentation answering questions on our Zulip chat, I realized that all the pieces were present but we did not have any overall example showing how to use them!
So I setup this new example based on a real life use-case our community users have submitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Testing of ALL your APIs</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/continuous-testing-all-your-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/continuous-testing-all-your-apis/</guid>
      <description>We talk a lot about asynchronous API lately at Microcks! We added many new innovative features taking advantage of the AsyncAPI specification. These are nice additions but we do not want them to hide the foundational essence of Microcks: offering you a consistent approach whatever the type of API. See our Why Microcks ? post for a refresher.
With this post we want to demonstrate how traditional REST API and event-based API can be used together and how Microcks can leverage your OpenAPI and AsyncAPI assets to ease the testing of scenarios involving both of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Microcks into Apicurio Keycloak</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/integrating-in-apicurio-keycloak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/integrating-in-apicurio-keycloak/</guid>
      <description>Microcks is an amazing tool that helps developers mock their APIs seamlessly using OpenAPI specs. This makes it easy for distributed teams to develop complex micro-services without having to wait for full development cycles to complete, thus maximising team efficiencies.
Apicurio Studio is another great tool to start creating your API documentations via a fully integrated OpenAPI spec editor and adds features like ability to view your documentation live as teams collaborate and edit specs on the editor in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Kafka Mocking and Testing</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/apache-kafka-mocking-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/apache-kafka-mocking-testing/</guid>
      <description>We see Apache Kafka being more and more commonly used as an event backbone in new organizations everyday. This is irrefutable. And while there are challenges adopting new frameworks and paradigms for the apps using Kafka, there is also a critical need to govern events and speed-up delivery. To improve time-to-market, organizations need to be able to develop without waiting for the whole system to be up and running ; and they will need to validate that the components talking with Kafka will send or receive correct messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.1.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.1.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.1.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are very thrilled to announce today Microcks 1.1.0 release — the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. What a ride it has been over the last months since 1.0.0 release and our announcement of AsyncAPI support !
We received a huge amount of positive feedback from our community including many newcomers. So we took the time to come back and explain where we are coming from and what is our project purpose: see the &amp;ldquo;Why Microcks ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Microcks?</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/why-microcks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/why-microcks/</guid>
      <description>Microcks recently reached a key milestone as we officially announced on Aug 11th 2020 the release of Microcks 1.0.0, being our first General Availability (GA) version. With it we deliver the promise of providing an enterprise-grade solution to speed up, secure and scale your API strategy for the digital era — whatever the type of services or API.
As we have received massive supportive feedback since August, we consider it a great opportunity to take some time to come back to the reasons why we started Microcks, especially for the newcomers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.0.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.0.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.0.0-release/</guid>
      <description>Today is a very special day as we launch Microcks 1.0.0 and as it materializes a vision we had 18 months ago when starting investing more time on what was just a fun side-project at that time. That vision was about building one simple, scalable and consolidating tool for all the Enterprise services mocking and testing needs — whatever the type of services or API: green-field or legacy. Today, Microcks is the only Open source Kubernetes native tool for API Mocking and Testing supporting REST APIs, SOAP WebServices and now asynchronous / event-driven APIs!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Microcks on AWS for a test drive 🧪</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/install-microcks-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/install-microcks-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>Whilst we recommend installing Microcks on Kubernetes for easy management and enhanced capabilities, it can also be deployed onto a regular Virtual Machine. This post details how you can setup Microcks onto an AWS EC2 instance if you’re familiar with this environment and want a quick test drive. It takes something like 6–7 minutes to complete from end-to-end. It’s an illustration of official setup documentation.
This will give you a Microcks installation on an AWS EC2 instance running Ubuntu 18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 0.9.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-0.9.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-0.9.0-release/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce Microcks release 0.9.0 — the Open source Kubernetes native tool for API Mocking and Testing. This new version introduces a tremendous amount of enhancements and new features.
Big thanks to our growing community for all the work done, the raised issues and the collected feedback during the last 5 months to make it possible.
This release was the preparation to become more Enterprise-grade, and we are glad that Microcks is in production in more and more medium to large organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>