<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorials on API Mocking and Testing | Microcks.io</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorials on API Mocking and Testing | Microcks.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting started</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/getting-started/</guid><description>Quickstart In this tutorial, you will discover Microcks mocking features by re-using a simple REST API sample. For that: you will run Microcks on your local machine, then load a sample provided by the Microcks team, explore the web user interface and then interact with an API mock.
The easiest way to get started with Microcks is using Docker or Podman with our ephemral all-in-one Microcks distribution.
In your terminal issue the following command - maybe replacing 8585 by another port of your choice if this one is not free:</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Tests</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/getting-started-tests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/getting-started-tests/</guid><description>Quickstart (continue) with Tests Now that you have finished the Getting started guide, you should have a Microcks installation up-and-running and filled with some samples from the Microcks repository. The goal of this page is to show you how you can use Microcks to achieve Contract Testing for your API, either manually from the UI or in an automated way using the Microcks CLI tooling.
If you have not done it in the previous step, you will need to load one of Microcks samples: the Pastry API - 2.</description></item><item><title>Your 1st REST mock</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-rest-mock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-rest-mock/</guid><description>Overview This tutorial is a step-by-step walkthrough on how to use OpenAPI v3 Specification to specify your mocks for your API. This is hands-on introduction to OpenAPI Conventions reference that brings all details on conventions being used.
We will go through a practical example based on the famous PetStore API. We&amp;rsquo;ll build the reference petstore-1.0.0-openapi.yaml file by iterations, highlighting the details to get you starting with mocking OpenAPI on Microcks.</description></item><item><title>Your 1st GraphQL mock</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-graphql-mock/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-graphql-mock/</guid><description>Overview This tutorial is a step-by-step walkthrough on how to use GraphQL schemas to get mocks for your GraphQL API. This is hands-on introduction to GraphQL Conventions reference that brings all details on conventions being used.
We will go through a practical example based on the famous PetStore API. We’ll build the reference petstore-1.0.graphql file by iterations, highlighting the details to get you starting with mocking GraphQL on Microcks.
To complete this tutorial, you will need one additional tool: Postman to define sample data that will be used by your mocks.</description></item><item><title>Your 1st gRPC mock</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-grpc-mock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-grpc-mock/</guid><description>Overview This tutorial is a step-by-step walkthrough on how to use a gRPC / Protocol Buffers specification to get mocks for your gRPC Service. This is hands-on introduction to gRPC Conventions reference that brings all details on conventions being used.
We will go through a practical example based on the famous PetStore API. We’ll build the reference petstore-v1.proto file by iterations, highlighting the details to get you starting with mocking gRPC on Microcks.</description></item><item><title>Your 1st Soap mock</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-soap-mock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-soap-mock/</guid><description>Overview This tutorial is a step-by-step walkthrough on how to use SoapUI projects to get mocks for your SOAP WebService. This is hands-on introduction to SoapUI Conventions reference that brings all details on conventions being used.
We will go through a practical example based on the famous PetStore API. We’ll build the reference petstore-1.0-soapui-project.xml file by iterations, highlighting the details to get you starting with mocking SOAP WebServices on Microcks.</description></item><item><title>Your 1st AsyncAPI on Kafka mock</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-asyncapi-mock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/tutorials/first-asyncapi-mock/</guid><description>Overview This tutorial is a step-by-step walkthrough on how to use AsyncAPI v3 Specification to specify your mocks for your Asynchronous and Event-Driven API. This is hands-on introduction to AsyncAPI Conventions reference that brings all details on conventions being used.
We will go through a practical example based on the famous PetStore API. We’ll build the reference petstore-1.0.0-asyncapi.yaml file by iterations, highlighting the details to get you starting with mocking AsyncAPI on Microcks.</description></item></channel></rss>