<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Administration on API Mocking and Testing | Microcks.io</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/</link><description>Recent content in Administration on API Mocking and Testing | Microcks.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Organizing Repository</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/organizing-repository/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/organizing-repository/</guid><description>Overview This guide walks through the different techniques for organinzing your API &amp;amp; Services repository content in Microcks. As you import more and more artifacts into Microcks, it can be come difficult to find the API you&amp;rsquo;re looking for! Microcks proposes handling by putting labels 🏷️ on APIs &amp;amp; Services or Importer Jobs of your repository. Labels are a very flexible way to map your own organizational structures with loose coupling.</description></item><item><title>Managing Users</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/users/</guid><description>Overview This guide will show you how to use the Users Management capabilities of the Microcks Web UI.
Your can partially manage users directly from the Microcks UI. &amp;ldquo;Partially&amp;rdquo; means that you are able to manage a user&amp;rsquo;s rolesand groups within Microcks but that you&amp;rsquo;re not able to create a new user. This action is reserved to your Identity Provider used through Keycloak configuration or to Keycloak itself if you choose to use it as a provider.</description></item><item><title>Accessing secured Resources</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/secrets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/secrets/</guid><description>Overview Quickly after your initial experience with Microcks, you&amp;rsquo;ll realize that it needs to access some of your private resources for smooth integration in your lifecycle. Typically:
Loading Artifacts may require accessing secured external resources such as Git repositories, Launching tests may require accessing protected HTTPS endpoints or internal message brokers. This guide will explain you what is the concept of Secret in Microcks, how to manage those Secrets and how to use them when defining an Importer Job.</description></item><item><title>Snapshotting/restoring Repository</title><link>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/snapshots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://microcks.io/documentation/guides/administration/snapshots/</guid><description>Overview This guide will teach you what are Microcks Snapshots and what are their use-case sweet spots. As an administrator, you will learn how to select the elements you would like to Snapshots and how to import a previous Snapshot to restore content.
🚨 Prerequisites
Users can only be managed by Microcks admin - we mean people having the admin role assigned. In order to be able to retrieve the list of users and operate changes, the user should also have manage-users and manage-clients roles from realm-management Keycloak internal client.</description></item></channel></rss>