<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microcks Blog on Microcks.io</title>
    <link>https://microcks.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microcks Blog on Microcks.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://microcks.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Join the Microcks Adopters list and Empower the vibrant open source Community 🙌</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/join-adopters-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/join-adopters-list/</guid>
      <description>Open source software has revolutionized the way enterprises develop and deploy their applications. It fosters collaboration, innovation, and cost-effectiveness, enabling organizations to build secure and robust solutions while leveraging the collective knowledge and expertise of a vast and diverse community.
Microcks, the Kubernetes-Native multi-protocol open source enterprise mocking and testing API solution, is an excellent example of the power of open source projects. In this blog post, we invite enterprises and community users to join the Microcks adopters list, showcasing their support for the project and contributing to its growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks&#39; Backstage integration to centralize all your APIs in a software catalog 🧩</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/backstage-integration-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/backstage-integration-launch/</guid>
      <description>Identifying and managing software assets has always been a challenge! It became more and more difficult these years with the blast of multi-cloud deployments and practices like microservices. Fortunately, Backstage comes to the rescue and tends to become a standard for developer portals. Today, we are excited to announce an integration between Microcks and Backstage to ease the management of API related assets.
Contributed to the CNCF by Spotify, Backstage is, according to their website:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J.B. Hunt: Mock It till You Make It with Microcks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/jb-hunt-mock-it-till-you-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/jb-hunt-mock-it-till-you-make-it/</guid>
      <description>Collaboration in the enterprise has many challenges which can become pitfalls and roadblocks that threaten to slow agile software development to a complete standstill. Here, I’ll share how Microcks helped the Engineering and Technology team overcome obstacles and accelerate development and delivery at J.B. Hunt Transport Services, Inc.
At J.B. Hunt, it’s common for multiple software engineering teams to work in parallel across domains and products to deliver new features for our award-winning J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.7.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.7.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.7.0-release/</guid>
      <description>The end of the winter season ☃️ is coming. But unlike our fellow hibernators 🐻, instead of living off stores of fat, our amazing community has worked hard on yet another Microcks release - yes, version 1.7.0 is out 👏
In a few words, here are the highlights of this new release:
  Some new protocols &amp;amp; connectors, you asked for it so: NATS, Google PubSub, and Postman Workspace are now available,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks partners with Postman to shape next-gen multi-protocol API tooling ⭐️</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-partners-with-postman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-partners-with-postman/</guid>
      <description>I’m feeling proud and honored to let you know that we’re partnering with Postman, the leading platform for API development, to define the future of multi-protocol API tooling 🚀
From day one, Microcks had the vision of a multi-protocol API ecosystem due to the ubiquitous nature of API. This is especially true at the enterprise level where the technology strata are built over the years. This vision has been confirmed by our growing user base and community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks Docker Desktop Extension 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/docker-desktop-extension-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/docker-desktop-extension-launch/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce the release of Microcks&#39; Docker Desktop Extension as we always love to support and improve the lives of our community members. 🎉
 It has never been simpler to set up and use Microcks on a laptop or from anywhere you need or want thanks to Docker Desktop Extension. 🙌
 Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick look at how it functions and what it adds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.6.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.6.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.6.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce the 1.6.0 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. It has been an intense summer time for us as the previous 1.5.2 is just 3 months old!
We’re now “back to work” and happy to release many features that were requested by our community! In a few words, here are the highlights of this new release:
 Governance is certainly a huge topic and you’ll see how Microcks can bring significant insights regarding the Tests Conformance of your API, Observability can be tightly linked to Governance as well and Microcks has new APIs to bring you functional and technical observability, And of course a lot more: Direct API concepts enhancements and a coming Docker Desktop extension among many others!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.5.2 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.5.2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.5.2-release/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to announce the 1.5.2 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. This is mainly an “Enhancement release” pushing further the Microcks’ Hub and Marketplace we introduced a few weeks ago.
In our vision, the Hub will hold a central place that will allow Microcks users to easily reuse curated API Mocks &amp;amp; Test suites in a single click - but also to share and publish their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks’ hub and marketplace!</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-hub-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-hub-announcement/</guid>
      <description>We are very proud to announce the launch of Microcks’ community hub and free marketplace 👉 hub.microcks.io! This has been discussed and requested many times within our community and here we are 🙌
The goal of this new community website is to collect, curate and share API Mocks &amp;amp; Test suites for being installed and used within any Microcks instance in a single click.
 If like us you like craft beers, let’s do the analogy between this announcement 👉 freely sharing API Mocks and Test suites and a brew bar!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.5.1 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.5.1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.5.1-release/</guid>
      <description>We are proud to announce the 1.5.1 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. We considered it a minor release this time as it “just” brought a new protocol binding and a lot of enhancements!
Once again this release is an illustration of how community-driven the roadmap is: AMQP and Swagger v2 support as well as more enhancements came directly from user requests. So thanks a lot to those who helped push up a new release with significant features once again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.5.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.5.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.5.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce the 1.5.0 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. Just three months have passed after the previous iteration, and our supporters in the community helped us push up a new release with significant features once again. Thanks a lot to all of them 👏
In line with our mantra, this release is the evidence of our vision of a unique tool with a consistent approach for speeding up the delivery and governing the lifecycle of ALL kinds of APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL features in Microcks: what to expect?</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/graphql-features-what-to-expect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/graphql-features-what-to-expect/</guid>
      <description>In various 2021 reports, GraphQL has been spotted as one of the most exciting technologies to consider for APIs. It is a query language and a runtime for fulfilling those queries with your existing data. GraphQL provides a complete and understandable description of the data in your API, gives clients the power to ask for exactly what they need and nothing more, makes it easier to evolve APIs over time, and enables powerful developer tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.4.1 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.4.1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.4.1-release/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled to announce today the 1.4.1 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. This release is another demonstration of the ability of Microcks to play on both sides with new Enterprise related features but also enhancement towards the Developer eXperience.
You’ll see that we put a lot of effort (and love ❤️) into listening and implementing feedback and ideas from our community: the number of people that suggested, contributed or helped amplify Microcks reach in communities is huge!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Async Features with Docker Compose</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/async-features-with-docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/async-features-with-docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>For some weeks now, many users from the Microcks community were asking for playing with AsyncAPI related features without having to setup a Minikube or a full Kubernetes instance. And Docker-Compose is the perfect match for that! We were at first reluctant as it is an additional configuration to support&amp;hellip; but developers experience FTW! 💪
This blog post is a detailed walkthrough on how to use Asynchronous related features with Docker-Compose using the new set of compose files shipped in Microcks master branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.3.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.3.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.3.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are so proud and happy to share this new major and important Microcks release two months in advance based on our initial roadmap! Yes, this was yet another big challenge 🎉 Kudos to our community users and partners for supporting and pushing us to this momentum.
Nothing could have been done without all your feedback and contributions 👏
So why is this release so special? First, We always stay on our principles and we are still applying our mantra for supporting ALL kinds of APIs and being community driven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.2.1 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.2.1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.2.1-release/</guid>
      <description>We are very glad to announce today the 1.2.1 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. This is mainly an “Enhancement release” pushing further the features we introduced within the previous 1.2.0 release.
With this release, we are still applying our mantra for supporting ALL kinds of APIs and being community driven. Want some keywords on what’s in this 1.2.1 release? We’ve been working on OpenAPI v3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating CloudEvents with AsyncAPI and Microcks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/simulating-cloudevents-with-asyncapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/simulating-cloudevents-with-asyncapi/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: CloudEvents and AsyncAPI are complementary specifications that help define your Event Driven Architecture. Microcks allows simulation of CloudEvent to speed-up and ensure autonomy of development teams.
  The rise of Event Driven Architecture (EDA) is a necessary evolution step towards cloud-native applications. Events are the ultimate weapon to decouple your microservices within your architecture. They are bringing great benefits like space and time decoupling, better resiliency and elasticity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podman Compose support in Microcks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/podman-compose-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/podman-compose-support/</guid>
      <description>While Docker is still the #1 option for software packaging and installation on the developer laptop, Podman is gaining traction. Podman advertises itself as a drop-in replacement for Docker. Just put alias podman=docker and you would be good to go, they said 😉
Whilst the reality is a bit more nuanced, we made the necessary adjustment to make it as simple. Today it is a pleasure to contribute back this adaptation to the Microcks community!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.2.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.2.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.2.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to announce the 1.2.0 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. With this new release, we are pursuing further our vision of a unique tool and consistent approach for speeding up the delivery and governing the lifecycle of ALL kinds of APIs - whether synchronous or asynchronous.
In this release, we put a lot of effort (and love ❤️) into listening and implementing feedback and ideas from our community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Dispatching and Constraints for mocks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/advanced-dispatching-constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/advanced-dispatching-constraints/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to explain the advanced dispatching and constraint features available when mocking a REST API using Microcks. As I recently went again through the documentation answering questions on our Zulip chat, I realized that all the pieces were present but we did not have any overall example showing how to use them!
So I setup this new example based on a real life use-case our community users have submitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Testing of ALL your APIs</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/continuous-testing-all-your-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/continuous-testing-all-your-apis/</guid>
      <description>We talk a lot about asynchronous API lately at Microcks! We added many new innovative features taking advantage of the AsyncAPI specification. These are nice additions but we do not want them to hide the foundational essence of Microcks: offering you a consistent approach whatever the type of API. See our Why Microcks ? post for a refresher.
With this post we want to demonstrate how traditional REST API and event-based API can be used together and how Microcks can leverage your OpenAPI and AsyncAPI assets to ease the testing of scenarios involving both of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Microcks into Apicurio Keycloak</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/integrating-in-apicurio-keycloak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/integrating-in-apicurio-keycloak/</guid>
      <description>Microcks is an amazing tool that helps developers mock their APIs seamlessly using OpenAPI specs. This makes it easy for distributed teams to develop complex micro-services without having to wait for full development cycles to complete, thus maximising team efficiencies.
Apicurio Studio is another great tool to start creating your API documentations via a fully integrated OpenAPI spec editor and adds features like ability to view your documentation live as teams collaborate and edit specs on the editor in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Kafka Mocking and Testing</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/apache-kafka-mocking-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/apache-kafka-mocking-testing/</guid>
      <description>We see Apache Kafka being more and more commonly used as an event backbone in new organizations everyday. This is irrefutable. And while there are challenges adopting new frameworks and paradigms for the apps using Kafka, there is also a critical need to govern events and speed-up delivery. To improve time-to-market, organizations need to be able to develop without waiting for the whole system to be up and running ; and they will need to validate that the components talking with Kafka will send or receive correct messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.1.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.1.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.1.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are very thrilled to announce today Microcks 1.1.0 release — the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing. What a ride it has been over the last months since 1.0.0 release and our announcement of AsyncAPI support !
We received a huge amount of positive feedback from our community including many newcomers. So we took the time to come back and explain where we are coming from and what is our project purpose: see the &amp;ldquo;Why Microcks ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Microcks?</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/why-microcks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/why-microcks/</guid>
      <description>Microcks recently reached a key milestone as we officially announced on Aug 11th 2020 the release of Microcks 1.0.0, being our first General Availability (GA) version. With it we deliver the promise of providing an enterprise-grade solution to speed up, secure and scale your API strategy for the digital era — whatever the type of services or API.
As we have received massive supportive feedback since August, we consider it a great opportunity to take some time to come back to the reasons why we started Microcks, especially for the newcomers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 1.0.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.0.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-1.0.0-release/</guid>
      <description>Today is a very special day as we launch Microcks 1.0.0 and as it materializes a vision we had 18 months ago when starting investing more time on what was just a fun side-project at that time. That vision was about building one simple, scalable and consolidating tool for all the Enterprise services mocking and testing needs — whatever the type of services or API: green-field or legacy. Today, Microcks is the only Open source Kubernetes native tool for API Mocking and Testing supporting REST APIs, SOAP WebServices and now asynchronous / event-driven APIs!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Microcks on AWS for a test drive 🧪</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/install-microcks-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/install-microcks-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>Whilst we recommend installing Microcks on Kubernetes for easy management and enhanced capabilities, it can also be deployed onto a regular Virtual Machine. This post details how you can setup Microcks onto an AWS EC2 instance if you’re familiar with this environment and want a quick test drive. It takes something like 6–7 minutes to complete from end-to-end. It’s an illustration of official setup documentation.
This will give you a Microcks installation on an AWS EC2 instance running Ubuntu 18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcks 0.9.0 release 🚀</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-0.9.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/blog/microcks-0.9.0-release/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce Microcks release 0.9.0 — the Open source Kubernetes native tool for API Mocking and Testing. This new version introduces a tremendous amount of enhancements and new features.
Big thanks to our growing community for all the work done, the raised issues and the collected feedback during the last 5 months to make it possible.
This release was the preparation to become more Enterprise-grade, and we are glad that Microcks is in production in more and more medium to large organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
