<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>releases on Microcks.io</title>
    <link>https://microcks.io/categories/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in releases on Microcks.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://microcks.io/categories/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>News about Microcks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/news/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Releases Microcks core 1.8.0 on 17 Oct 2023 As the seasons transition, we are excited to unveil the 1.8.0 release of Microcks, the CNCF&amp;rsquo;s open-source cloud-native tool for API Mocking and Testing, right on the cusp of winter! ❄️ 🚀
With 47 resolved issues and 5 external PR (from new contributors) - This new release brings you a wave of new features, including AI Copilot, support for HAR artifacts, OAuth2 secured endpoint testing, Microcks super light Uber image, Testcontainers official module, two developer-friendly buttons for easy interactions (Copy as curl command and Add to your CI/CD), and an enhanced contextual help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Microcks release notes</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/news/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/news/history/</guid>
      <description>Older Releases Microcks core 1.4.1 on 15 Oct 2021 We are thrilled to announce the 1.4.1 release that is another demonstration of the ability of Microcks to play on both sides with new Enterprise related features but also enhancement towards the Developer eXperience. Here are the highlighted changes of this release:
 The ability to have Repository multi-tenancy for better management of large-scaled repositories, The introduction of APIMetadata artifact for scaling labeling in Microcks, The support of all Async features on developer&amp;rsquo;s laptop through Docker-Compose, The introduction of Microcks extensions for OpenAPI and AsyncAPI specifications,  Check out our release notes!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
