<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>releases on Microcks.io</title>
    <link>https://microcks.io/categories/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in releases on Microcks.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://microcks.io/categories/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>News about Microcks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/news/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Releases Microcks core 1.0.0 on 11 Aug 2020 We are very pleased to announce the Microcks release 1.0.0!
 The major announcement is the support of AsyncAPI for Event-driven APIs, A lot of security enhancements including major components versions bump, better Keycloak reuse and container images systematic scanning.  Check out our Medium release notes!
You can also check GitHub milestone for the full list of closed issues.
0.9.2 on 19 May 2020 Version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Microcks release notes</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/news/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/news/history/</guid>
      <description>Older Releases Microcks core 0.8.0 on 27 Nov 2019 We just release version 0.8.0 of Microcks core! This release holds something like 40 issues fix!
Among some other stuffs, we now have:
 Support for media type negociation on REST mocks, Support of CORS policy for REST mocks, Support of PATCH and OPTIONS operations on REST mocks, Multi-format support for OpenAPI v3 examples, Addition of users management from the Microcks UI, Addition of custom JSON body dispatcher, Many UI improvements like embedded help, about modal and easier importer creation flow, Fix of HTTPS with custom certificates support for accessing private repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>