<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>releases on Microcks.io</title>
    <link>https://microcks.io/categories/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in releases on Microcks.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://microcks.io/categories/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>News about Microcks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/news/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Releases Microcks core 1.7.1 on 21 Jun 2023 The seasons follow one another and here’s a Microcks release just ready for summer ☀️. We’re proud to announce today the 1.7.1 release of Microcks - the Open source Kubernetes-native tool for API Mocking and Testing.
With 37 resolved issues - our record for a minor release - this release is an illustration of how community-driven the roadmap is: Amazon SQS &amp;amp; SNS support and Specifications goodies as well as many enhancements came directly from user requests and contributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Microcks release notes</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/news/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/news/history/</guid>
      <description>Older Releases Microcks core 1.4.1 on 15 Oct 2021 We are thrilled to announce the 1.4.1 release that is another demonstration of the ability of Microcks to play on both sides with new Enterprise related features but also enhancement towards the Developer eXperience. Here are the highlighted changes of this release:
 The ability to have Repository multi-tenancy for better management of large-scaled repositories, The introduction of APIMetadata artifact for scaling labeling in Microcks, The support of all Async features on developer&amp;rsquo;s laptop through Docker-Compose, The introduction of Microcks extensions for OpenAPI and AsyncAPI specifications,  Check out our release notes!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
