<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>releases on Microcks.io</title>
    <link>https://microcks.io/categories/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in releases on Microcks.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://microcks.io/categories/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>News about Microcks</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/news/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Releases Microcks core 1.2.0 on 21 Feb 2021 We are delighted to announce the 1.2.0 release of Microcks! Here are below the main highlights of this release:
 The support of Apache Avro as Event-driven APIs message encoding, as well as various schema registries. See our Kafka, Avro and Schema Registry guide The support of MQTT protocol for mocking and testing Event-driven APIs that may be related to the Internet of Things (IoT), New template functions for bringing rich dynamic mocking responses, New FALLBACK dispatcher for smarter routing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Microcks release notes</title>
      <link>https://microcks.io/news/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microcks.io/news/history/</guid>
      <description>Older Releases Microcks core 0.8.0 on 27 Nov 2019 We just release version 0.8.0 of Microcks core! This release holds something like 40 issues fix!
Among some other stuffs, we now have:
 Support for media type negociation on REST mocks, Support of CORS policy for REST mocks, Support of PATCH and OPTIONS operations on REST mocks, Multi-format support for OpenAPI v3 examples, Addition of users management from the Microcks UI, Addition of custom JSON body dispatcher, Many UI improvements like embedded help, about modal and easier importer creation flow, Fix of HTTPS with custom certificates support for accessing private repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>